

💌 ddetone@umich.edu | 🎢 danieldetone.com | 🖸 ddetone | 🛅 ddetone | 💆 @ddetone | Berkeley, CA

Research Interests

My research interests lie at the intersection of Deep Learning, Computer Vision, 3D Geometry and their applications in Augmented Reality and Robotics. I enjoy studying how deep learning can be applied to computer vision problems including keypoint detection, image matching, relocalization, multi-view reconstruction, visual SLAM, depth estimation, homography estimation, camera calibration and bundle-adjustment.

Experience

Magic Leap Sunnyvale, CA

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2015 - 2020

- Invented novel Deep SLAM techniques (see MagicPoint, SuperPoint, SuperGlue)
- Invented robust camera calibration technique (see Deep ChArUco)
- Researched differentiable Bundle Adjustment in PyTorch for supervising neural networks
- Researched LSTMs for pose estimation and gesture recognition
- · Researched CNNs for geometric tasks like homography estimation, optical flow, and relative pose estimation
- Built custom real-time SLAM backend with Ceres-Solver using both Python and C++
- Maintained internal fork of the Caffe library used by a team of 20+ engineers
- Supervised by Dr. Tomasz Malisiewicz and Dr. Andrew Rabinovich

DROP Lab Ann Arbor, MI

RESEARCHER Summer 2015

- Explored the use of 3D spatial CNNs for 3D semantic segmentation
- Wrote custom CUDA kernels in Caffe to enable 3D convolutions on GPU
- Supervised by Prof. Johnson-Roberson

Occipital San Francisco, CA

COMPUTER VISION INTERN Summer 2014

- Developed and shipped core components of the Structure SDK 0.1.2 and 0.2 releases
- Build two iPad prototype apps leveraging RGBD Dense SLAM, SceneKit on iOS and OpenGL ES
- Supervised by Jeffery Powers

APRIL Robotics LAB Ann Arbor, MI

RESEARCHER Fall 2013 - Winter 2014

- Led development of four person team for an automated lecture recording system
- Prototyped real-time object tracking systems using particle and Kalman filters in OpenCV + MATLAB
- Reduced system hardware costs from \$15,000 to less than \$3,000
- · Supervised by Prof. Edwin Olson

Computer Vision Lab Ann Arbor, MI

Summer 2013 RESEARCHER

- · Adapted the indoor PTAM SLAM framework for use in outdoor autonomous driving localization • Improved localization accuracy from 85% to 98% 1m error in the KITTI dataset
- · Supervised by Prof. Silvio Savarese

Education

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

M.S.E. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING: SYSTEMS (SIGNAL PROCESSING AND INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS)

2013 - 2015

B.S.E. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING (MINOR IN INTERNATIONAL STUDIES)

2008 - 2013

Skills_

Languages Python, C++, JavaScript, MATLAB, LaTeX

Frameworks PyTorch, Tensorflow, Caffe, Ceres-Solver, OpenCV

Publications

P.-E. Sarlin, D. DeTone, T. Malisiewicz, and A. Rabinovich. SuperGlue: Learning Feature Matching with Graph Neural Networks. In CVPR, 2020.

D. Hu, D. DeTone, and T. Malisiewicz.. Deep Charuco: Dark Charuco Marker Pose Estimation. In CVPR, 2019.

D. DeTone, T. Malisiewicz, and A. Rabinovich. Self-Improving Visual Odometry. arXiv Technical Report. December, 2018.

D. DeTone, T. Malisiewicz, and A. Rabinovich. SuperPoint: Self-Supervised Interest Point Detection and Description. In CVPRW, 2018.

D. DeTone, T. Malisiewicz, and A. Rabinovich. Toward Geometric Deep SLAM. arXiv Technical Report. July, 2017.

D. DeTone, T. Malisiewicz, and A. Rabinovich. Deep Image Homography Estimation. In RSSW, 2016.

DANIEL DETONE · RÉSUMÉ **SEPTEMBER 13, 2020**